Diego Grados Bedoya

I am a quality-driven bioscience engineer and applied statistician using interdisciplinary approaches to address sustainable development challenges in agriculture, focused on soil-crop-atmosphere interactions, agroecosystems analysis and remote sensing. During my involvement in international research projects with multidisciplinary partners, I have demonstrated excellent teamwork and communication skills. I am proficient in programming languages for data-processing applications and process-based modelling. I have also cultivated my enthusiasm for the creation of integrated assessments, focusing on the data science to translate information into knowledge.

Personal Data

Address: Scandiasporet 9A, 4mf, 8930 Randers NØ, Denmark

Phone: (+32) 485 02 20 07 Email: diegogradosb@gmail.com

Web: https://diegogradosb.github.io/

Relevant Experience

SEP 2020 -PRESENT Postdoctoral Researcher - AARHUS UNIVERSITY, Aarhus - Denmark

Climate and Water - Agroecology Department - Faculty of Technical Sciences

- Mitigation strategies of greenhouse gas emissions using process-based modeling and data-processing applications.
- Systematic review and meta-analysis of greenhouse gas emissions of agroecosystems.
- Dissemination of results in seminars, workshops, peer-reviewed journals and international conferences.

Reference: Prof. Dr. Diego ABALOS

JAN 2020 -MAR 2020 Researcher - KU LEUVEN, Leuven - Belgium

Mechatronics, Biostatistics and Sensors - Biosystems Department - Faculty of Bioscience Engineering

- Developing of multi-target and system modeling methodologies for the agroecosystems' sustainability assessment.
- Dissemination of research results in workshops and peer-reviewed journals. Mentoring of PhD thesis students.

APR 2016 -DEC 2019

PhD Researcher

- Developing of multi-target and system modeling methodologies for the agroecosystems' sustainability assessment.
 - Dissemination of results in seminars, workshops, peer-reviewed journals and international conferences.
- Mentoring and supervision of BSc and MSc thesis students in Peru (UNALM and UNCP) and Belgium (KU Leuven).

Reference: Prof. Dr. Eddie SCHREVENS

Nov 2014 -Apr 2019 Research Assistant - VLIR/UOS-UNALM PROJECT, Lima - Peru Strengthening of Smallholder Horticultural Systems Subproject

- Co-leading the study of soil-crop-environment interactions in the Peruvian Costal Desert.
- Installation of soil, meteorological and irrigation equipment.
- Design, installation and analysis of agricultural experiments under drip irrigation systems.

References: Prof. Dr. Eddie Schrevens, Prof. Dr. Guido Wyseure, Prof. Dr. Jan Diels

SEP 2013 -DEC 2018

Research Officer - VLIR/UOS-UNALM PROJECT, Junin - Peru Sustainable Agriculture in the Central Peruvian Andes Subproject

- Leading the design, installation and evaluation of agricultural experiments under rainfed conditions.
- Consolidation of rational databases, development of soil-crop-atmosphere models and advanced statistical techniques.
- Analysis of agroecosystems using participatory approaches along with biophysical and biochemical assessments.

References: Prof. Dr. Eddie Schrevens, Prof. Dr. Sady García

FEB 2013 -APR 2019

Research Officer - VLIR/UOS-UNALM PROJECT, Junin | Lima - Peru

Drone Technology in Agriculture Subproject

- Leading the feasibility study for uses of drone technology in agroecosystems.
- In charge of drone flights in Peruvian's Andes and Arid regions. Implementation of photogrammetric and GIS databases.
- Development of mathematical and statistical workflows for land use classification and field experiments' assessment.

References: Prof. Dr. Eddie Schrevens, MSc. Dries Raymaekers

JAN 2012 -DEC 2018

Research Officer - VLIR/UOS-UNALM PROJECT, Junin - Peru

Watersheds Management Subproject

- Leading the study of soil-crop-environment interactions and hydrology in the Peruvian Central Andes.
- Installation of soil, climatological and hydrometric equipment.
- Implementation of databases, application of hydrological models and assessment of rainfall-runoff relations.

References: Prof. Dr. Eduardo Chávarri, Prof. Dr. Guido Wyseure

Education

APR 2016 - **PhD in Bioscience Engineering**, *Mechatronics*, *Biostatistics and Sensors* - KU Leuven, Belgium

DEC 2019 Thesis Title: "Multi-target methodologies for the improvement of agricultural systems research

- Study cases at system and field level". | Advisor: Prof. Dr. Eddie Schrevens

JAN 2007 - **BSc in Agricultural Engineering**, *Water Resources* - Agrarian National University La Molina , Peru

DEC 2011 Honor Thesis Title: "Analysis of flood peaks in small Andean watersheds, Junin Department,

Peru (2011-2012 Period)". | Advisor: Prof. Dr. Eduardo Chávarri

Publications

- 1. **Grados, D.,** Reynafarje, X., Schrevens, E., 2020. A methodological approach to assess canopy NDVI–based tomato dynamics under irrigation treatments. *Journal of Agricultural Water Management*, 240, 106208. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.agwat.2020.106208.
- 2. **Grados, D.,** Schrevens, E., 2020. Cassava NDVI analysis: A nonlinear mixed model approach based on UAV-imagery. *PFG Journal of Photogrammetry, Remote Sensing and Geoinformation Science*. http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s41064-020-00116-x.
- 3. **Grados, D.,** García, S., Schrevens, E., 2020. Assessing the potato yield gap in the Peruvian Central Andes. *Journal of Agricultural Systems*, 181, 102817. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.agsy.2020.102817.
- 4. **Grados, D.,** Schrevens, E., 2019. Multidimensional analysis of environmental impacts from potato agricultural production in the Peruvian Central Andes. *Science of The Total Environment*, 663, 927–934. http://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2019.01.414.

Relevant Conference Proceedings [PEER-REVIEWED]

- Grados, D., García, S., Schrevens, E., Nitrogen and water use efficiency under rain-fed potato agriculture: An experimental study. *Acta Horticulturae* (1253, 243–252). *International Symposium on Water and Nutrient Relations and Management of Horticultural Crops*, Istanbul, Turkey, 12-16 Aug 2018. http://doi.org/10.17660/actahortic.2019.1253.33.
- Reynafarje, X., **Grados, D.**, Casas, A., Schrevens, E., Effect of water stress after flowering stage on tomato crop yield and soil water content in the semi-arid Peruvian coastline. *Acta Horticulturae* (1253, 279–286). *International Symposium on Water and Nutrient Relations and Management of Horticultural Crops*, Istanbul, Turkey, 12-16 Aug 2018. http://doi.org/10.17660/actahortic.2019.1253.37.
- Grados, D., Gil, R., Raymaekers, D., Schrevens, E., Developing of an automated UAV-based RGB imagery workflow analysis for land use evaluation. *European Federation for Information Technology in Agriculture, Food and the Environment*, Montpellier, France, 02-06 Jul 2017. ISBN: 978-2-85362-686-6.
- Grados, D., Vetters, E., Heuts, R., Schrevens, E., A model based technical sustainability analysis of potato production systems in the Mantaro Valley, Central Highlands, Peru. *Acta Horticulturae* (1154, 155-152). Symposium on Applications of Modelling as an Innovative Technology in the Horticultural Supply Chain, Wageningen, The Netherlands, 11-14 Oct 2015. http://doi.org/10.17660/actahortic. 2017.1154.20.
- Grados, D., Vera, J., Schrevens, E., Corn-faba bean associations in the Peruvian Central Andes. *Acta Horticulturae* (1128, 79-88). *International Symposium on Horticulture in Developing Countries and World Food Production*, Brisbane, Australia, 19-22 Aug 2014. http://doi.org/10.17660/actahortic. 2016.1128.11.

Teaching Experience

- FA 2017 Applied Multivariate Statistical Analysis Master in Bioscience Engineering, KU Leuven
 - Teacher Assistant: I taught students how to analyze their databases using statistical software by leading R-tutorials. I was responsible for the practical sessions on data wrangling and visualization, matrix algebra, R-programming and advanced multivariate techniques. [80 students]
- FA 2019 Biological Production Systems Bachelor in Bioscience Engineering, **KU Leuven**Teacher Assistant: I guided students during the discussion and practical sessions to assess agroecosystems. I taught them the essentials of process-based mathematical modelling and supported them on the development of their research papers. [25 students]
- SP 2016 Ecosystems Modelling Master in Bioscience Engineering, **KU Leuven**Teacher Assistant: I taught students how to develop and utilize agroecosystems models at diverse scales by leading R-tutorials. I guided the practical sessions on mathematical and statistical concepts, data wrangling and visualization, R-programming. I taught them the fundamental topics on process-based modelling of agroecosystems: identification, implementation, calibration and validation. [10 students]

Fellowships

2020 **FONDECYT-CONCYTEC** Research Grant [5 500€]

2016 - 2019 VLIR/UOS-UNALM PhD Fellowship [82 000€]

2013 | 2014 | 2015 VLIR/UOS-UNALM International Scholar Fellowships [67 000€]

Languages

English: Full professional proficiency
French: Limited working proficiency
Spanish: Native/Bilingual

Technical Skills

Programming R, Python, MATLAB
Markup Markdown, LATEX

Other RStudio, Spyder, Office, QGIS, GRASS GIS, Git/GitHub, HTML/CSS, Make, HPC